(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T20:28:12.084043",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
今度こそ生き返れない
Even now I can't come back to life
そう思ったベッドの中
Inside the bed I thought so
気付けばカーテンの隙間から
When I noticed, through the gaps of the curtains
朝が生を教えた
The morning taught me life
ああ生きていたと安堵
Ah, the relief that I was alive
ああ生きてしまったと絶望
Ah, the despair that I have lived
まだやれるのか
Can I still do it?
まだやらなきゃならないのか
Do I still have to do it?
いっそ理不尽もがれてしまえば
If I were to be torn apart forcibly instead
なんてね
Just kidding
僕は元気です
I'm doing fine
そう言って今日も笑って
That's what I say, laughing again today
心はがらんどうです
My heart is hollow
大げさな音がする
There's an exaggerated sound
終末の鐘の音が
Is it the sound of the end's bell?
それでもこの声が それでもこの口が
Even so, this voice, even so, this mouth
それでもこの喉が千切れるくらい叫ぶよ
Even so, this throat will scream until it's torn
この腕が真白なこの羽が
This arm, these pure white wings
僕のこの命が生きたいと歌ってる
My life is singing that it wants to live
できるなら愛されたい
If I can, I want to be loved
許されたい ここにいたい 愛したい
I want to be forgiven, I want to be here, I want to love
誰も見てない夢を見るよ
I'll dream a dream no one has seen
だから僕を見てろよ
So keep looking at me
感情の捨て方はさ
How to throw away emotions
粗大ゴミのシールを貼る
Stick a bulky waste sticker on it
本音はいつだって強がりの裏
My true feelings are always behind my bravado
壊れる音がするんだよ
There's a sound of it crushing
ああ気付けなかった
Ah, I wasn't noticed
ああ気付いてほしいんだよ
Ah, I want you to notice
それでも君が
Even so, if you
笑ってくれるなら
Will laugh for me
いっそ心をなくしてしまえば
If I were to lose my heart instead
なんてね
Just kidding
敵わないなんて一瞬でも思ったら負けだ
If I think that I can't win for even a second, it's my loss
叶わないなんて一瞬でも過ぎたらやめだ
If I think that it won't come true for even a second, I'll quit
何万の諦める理由があったとしても
Even if there are tens of thousands of reasons to give up
たった一つの勇気がこの手の中に
There's only one courage in this hand
それでもこの声が それでもこの口が
Even so, this voice, even so, this mouth
それでもこの喉が千切れるくらい叫ぶよ
Even so, this throat will scream until it's torn
この腕が真白なこの羽が
This arm, these pure white wings
僕のこの命が生きたいと歌ってる
My life is singing that it wants to live
できるなら愛されたい
If I can, I want to be loved
許されたい ここにいたい 愛したい
I want to be forgiven, I want to be here, I want to love
誰も見てない夢を見るよ
I'll dream a dream no one has seen
だから僕を
So...
誰も見てない夢を見せるよ
I'll show you a dream no one has seen
だから僕を信じて
So believe in me
今度こそ生き返れない
Even now I can't come back to life
そう思ったベッドの中
Inside the bed I thought so
気付けばカーテンの隙間から
When I noticed, through the gaps of the curtains
朝が生を教えた
The morning taught me life
ああ生きていたと安堵
Ah, the relief that I was alive
ああ生きてしまったと絶望
Ah, the despair that I have lived
まだやれるのか
Can I still do it?
まだやらなくちゃならないのか
Do I still have to do it?
いっそ理不尽もがれてしまえば
If I were to be torn apart forcibly instead
なんてね
Just kidding
僕は元気です
I'm doing fine
出会えた 奇跡に
Meeting you was a miracle...
もう息が止まりそうだよ
It feels like my breath is stopping.
何を見ているの
What are you looking at
どこまでも澄んだ瞳で
with such endlessly clear eyes?
二人きりなら 許される
If it's just the two of us, we'll be forgiven
世界で
in this world,
全てが今 始まるから
because everything is starting right now.
君に出逢うために
Born just to meet you,
生まれたこと 伝えたいよ
I want to tell you that's why I was born.
そよ風も逃がさない
Not even letting the gentle breeze escape,
視線も全部
and all of my gaze...
ひりひりする声になるのさ ずっと
Turning into a burning, stinging voice, forever.
濁りのない 寂しき気持ちは
Feelings of loneliness without any cloudiness,
ヒリヒリするほど 高鳴ってる
throbbing so intensely it stings.
二人きり 未来へと
Just the two of us, flying into the future,
とべるんだ
we can fly away.
どこへ行くの 小さな
Where are you heading? Tears well up in my small self,
自分に涙あふれるけど 走り出せる
but I can start running.
どこへ行くの 小さな
Where are you heading, little one?
自分に涙あふれるけど 走り出せる
Tears overflow within me, yet I can run forth.
もしも はぐれたら
If we ever get separated,
体ごと 散ってみせる
I'll scatter my whole body apart.
花びらだった 一番の姿に
Returning to the shape of petals at our finest.
さあ 帰って
Now, return,
君の愛 求めて サービスするよ
seeking your love, I'll give you my all.
ずっと 君には
Forever to you,
ラブを送るよ
I will send my love.
満たされない 刺激的な気持ちが
Feelings of unfulfilled excitement
時を超えて 呼び合う
call out to each other across time.
二人きり 未来へと
Just the two of us, taking off into the future,
飛び立つんだ
we will soar away.
出会えた 奇跡に
Meeting you was a miracle...
もう息が止まりそうだよ
It feels like my breath is stopping.
繋いだ その手に
Holding your hand,
少し強くなれる気がする
I feel like I can be a little stronger.
出会えた 奇跡に
Meeting you was a miracle...
もう息が止まりそうだよ
It feels like my breath is stopping.
明日も 未来も どうしようもなく好きだよ
Tomorrow and the future too, I love you beyond words.
いつか僕らの上をスレスレに通り過ぎて
That plane that flew right above our heads
いったあの飛行機を
passing by us so close...
不思議なくらいに覚えている
I remember it so strangely well.
意味もないのに なぜか
For no reason at all, why...
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
On nights I cried over my own helplessness,
ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
I just wished to become stronger.
残酷な運命が定まってるとして
Even if a cruel fate is already set,
ただ一瞬 この一瞬 息ができるなら
if I can breathe for just a single moment...
遠くへ行け 遠くへ行けと 僕の中で誰かが歌う
"Go further, go further," someone sings inside of me
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
so passionately that I can't help it.
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と 悲しまないように笑える
So that you, with your swollen eyes, will smile,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this song is to become a hero like that.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
to the story that keeps rolling on.
「守りたい」なんて言えるほど 君が弱くはないのはわかってた
I knew you weren't weak enough for me to protect.
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ 君が大事だったんだ
I was even weaker, and you were precious to me.
「独りで生きていくんだ」なんてさ
Ever since that day when I blurted out,
変わっていく僕を笑えばいい 独りが怖い僕を
laugh at me changing, terrified of being alone.
蹴飛ばして噛み付いて 息もできなくて
Kick me, bite me, even if I can't breathe,
今は触っていたいんだ 君の心に
right now I want to touch your heart.
僕たちは きっといつか遠く離れた 太陽にすら手が届いて 夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
We will surely reach the sun and laugh at dawn.
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり おぼろげな街の向こうへ 手をつないで走っていけるはずなんだ
Running hand in hand toward the hazy town.
君と未来を盗み描く 捩りのないストーリーを
Stealing and sketching the future with you.
カサブタだらけ荒れ果てた日々が 削り削られ擦り切れた今が 君の言葉で蘇る
Days of desolation revived by your words.
鮮やかにも 現れていく 蛹のまま眠る魂を 食べかけのままで捨てたあの夢を もう一度取り戻そう
Taking back the soul and dream we left behind.
もう一度 遠くへ行け 遠くへ行けと 僕の中で誰かが歌う
"Go further," someone sings inside of me
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
so passionately that I can't help it.
遠くへ行け 遠くへ行けと 僕の中で誰かが歌う
"Go further," someone sings inside of me
どうしようもないほど熱烈に
so passionately that I can't help it.
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と 悲しまないように笑える
So that you will never be sad again,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
this song is to become a hero.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Farewell, raise your peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
to the story that keeps rolling on.
君と未来を盗み描く ひねりのないストーリーを
Stealing the future in a straightforward story.
さらば掲げろピースサイン 転がっていくストーリーを
Farewell, raise your peace sign.
考えてったってわからないし 青空の下、君を待った
Thinking about it gets me nowhere. I waited for you.
風が吹いた正午、昼下がりを抜け出す想像 進め方教わらないんだよ
Imagining escaping the afternoon. I was never taught.
君の目を見た 何も言えず僕は歩いた 考えてったってわからないし
I looked into your eyes and walked away.
青春なんてつまらないし 辞めた筈のピアノ
Youth is boring. The piano I should have quit...
考えてったってわからないし 青春なんてつまらないし 辞めた筈のピアノ
机を弾く癖が抜けないね 将来何してるんだろうね
I still play on my desk. What'll I do in future?
音楽はしてないといいね 困らないでよ
I hope I'm not making music. Don't worry.
心の中に一本線を引いても どうしても消えなかった
Even drawing a line, it wouldn't disappear.
今更なんだから もう思い出すな 間違えてるんだよ わかってない、あんた人間も
Too late, don't remember. You humans don't get it.
考えてったってわからないし
Even if I think it over, I don't get it.
青空の下、君を待った
Waiting for you under the blue sky.
風が吹いた正午、昼下がりを抜け出す想像
A midday breeze blowing, imagining slipping out of the afternoon.
ねえ、これからどうなるんだろうね 進め方教わらないんだよ
Hey, what's gonna happen from here? We're never taught how to move forward.
君の目を見た 何も言えず僕は歩いた
I looked into your eyes and walked off without a word.
考えてったってわからないし
Even if I think it over, I don't get it,
青春なんてつまらないし
Youth is just so dull.
辞めた筈のピアノ、机を弾く癖が抜けない
I can't break the habit of playing the piano I supposedly quit on my desk.
ねえ、将来何してるんだろうね 大人になったらわかったよ
Hey, what'll I be doing in the future? When I grew up, I figured it out.
何もしないさ
I won't be doing anything at all.
幸せな顔した人が憎いのはどう割り切ったらいいんだろう
How am I supposed to accept hating people who put on happy faces?
満たされない頭の奥の化け物みたいな劣等感
A monster-like inferiority complex deep inside my unsatisfied mind.
間違えてないよ
There's no way I'm wrong.
間違えてないよな
I can't be wrong, right?
なんだかんだってあんたら人間だ
No matter what, you're all human after all.
愛も救いも優しさも根拠がないなんて気味が悪いよ
It's so sickening how even love, salvation, and kindness have no basis.
ラブソングなんかが痛いのだって防衛本能だ
The aching feeling from love songs is just a self-preservation instinct.
どうでもいいか
Whatever, right?
考えてったってわからないし
Even if I think it over, I don't get it,
生きるだけで苦しいし 音楽とか儲からないし 歌詞とか適当でもいいよ
just living hurts so much, music doesn't make money, and lyrics can be sloppy.
どうでもいいや
Whatever.
間違えてないだろ
I can't be wrong, right?
間違えてないよな
間違えてるんだよ
I've got it all wrong.
わかってるんだ
I get it.
あんたら人間も
You humans too.
本当も愛も救いも優しさも人生もどうでもいいんだ
The truth, love, salvation, kindness, life—none of it matters.
正しい答えが言えないのだって防衛本能だ
Not being able to give the right answer is just a self-preservation instinct.
どうでもいいや
Whatever.
あんたのせいだ
It's your fault.
だから僕は音楽を辞めた
That's why I gave up on music.
今なんじゃない?
Isn't this the moment?
メラメラとたぎれ 眠っているだけの正義
Blaze up, the justice that's just been sleeping.
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to be your hero too, even someone like me.
かっこいい君には 僕じゃ頼りないのかななんて
To someone as cool as you, am I unreliable?
そりゃそうだよなだって
Well, of course you'd think that.
今もこうして迷ってる
Even now, I'm hesitating like this.
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero.
今なんじゃない?
Isn't this the moment?
メラメラとたぎれ こんな僕にも潜む正義が
Blaze up, the justice hidden even inside someone like me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて ほら気付けば手を握っている
Driven by an irresistible impulse, before I knew it, our hands were held.
一体全体 そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Just where are you going, carrying all that baggage?
ねえねえ待って 僕にちょっと預けてみては?
Hey, wait, why not entrust a little to me?
信じてばかりの僕と 信じるのが怖い君と
Me, who does nothing but believe, and you, who are afraid to believe.
今なんだじゃない？
What is it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Boiling with excitement,
眠っているだけの正義
Justice just sleeping.
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to be your hero too.
ギブとテイクさ
Give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero.
今なんだじゃない？
What is it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Boiling with excitement,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden in me.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて
You're cool and suffering,
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
It's my fault that I left you alone.
少し僕のせいなんだよなごめんね
I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what you should see is the real.
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now it's my turn to help.
抱えないで信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't carry it, believe in me, rely on me.
今なんだじゃない？
What is it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Boiling with excitement.
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice hidden in me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Overwhelmed by an irresistible impulse,
ほら気づけば手を握っている
Look, before you know it, we're holding hands.
いったいぜんたいそんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going carrying so much baggage?
ねえねえ待って僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Hey, wait, why not entrust a little to me?
信じてばかりの僕と
With me who believes only...
信じることが怖い君と
And you who are afraid to believe.
どちらが正しいのかなんて
Which one is right?
誰にも分からないさ
No one knows.
僕らだけの世界
Our own world,
ギブとテイクさ
Give and take.
補い合えた暁には同じ夢を見たい
In the dawn we survived, I want to dream the same dream.
今なんだじゃない？
What is it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Boiling with excitement,
こんな僕にも眠る正義が
The justice hidden in me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Overwhelmed by an irresistible impulse,
ほら気づけば手を握っている
Look, before you know it, we're holding hands.
ほっとけない
I can't leave you alone.
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going carrying so much baggage?
ほんのちょっと僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Just for a little while, why not entrust a little to me?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to be your hero too.
はい！皆さん！
Hi everyone!
天音かなた 卒業ライブと
The Amane Kanata Graduation Live...
いうことでですね
has finally begun!
こちらハッシュタグが
Regarding that hashtag...
あのしゃ、あまなつ卒業ライブでございますんで、ぜひこちらよろしくお願いします！
It's for the graduation live, so please use it!
1曲目に歌った今夜のフィネスは、実は初配信で歌おうか悩んでいた楽曲だったので
The second song I sang today was actually a track I was hesitating to sing for my first stream,
ここで歌えてすごくよかった！
so I'm really glad I could sing it here.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
小さい頃からね、ヒロインよりヒーローになりたいていう、僕のタイプだったので
Ever since I was little, I've loved heroes who want to be heroines,
そういった楽曲をたくさん歌わせていただきました！
so I got to sing many such songs.
次からは、ありがとねみんな、拍手もありがとう。
Thank you, everyone, for the applause!
次からはロックで感情をぶつけていくような
From now on, we're going to put our feelings into rock music!
調整しますね、ちょっとマイクが、調整しますんで
Let's adjust the mic...
聞いてください、劣等上等！
Please listen to "Rettou Joutou"!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Inferiority Superiority BRING IT ON
劣等上等
Inferiority Superiority
列島上等 不眠日本
Archipelago top sleeping Japan
子ども騙しのマセマティカ
Mathematica for tricking kids
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
Putting on airs of being a noble alarm
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんないね(It's boring)
Watching from above is boring (It's boring)
ほらもっと 間間違って上等
Hey, more, being wrong is superior
退屈に手をかけて
Hand on the boredom
こんなところじゃ終われない
I can't end it here
ぬるくて 気 が触れそう
It's lukewarm and I feel like I'm going crazy
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさようなら
Goodbye to playing pretend and acting
ダダダダ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I will become an adult
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all the sour and sweet things now
パパパパ 変わる時代
Pa pa pa, the changing era
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It's not just bad things, is it?
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
The past, sins, punishments, everything
素手で、愛で
With bare hands, with love
生き抜いてやり返すわ
I'll survive and strike back
yeah,挑発 あたし達はno doubt
yeah, provocation, we have no doubt
緑のアイツにばっか構ってんね
You're only paying attention to that green guy
さあburn up
Now burn up
いつになったら貰える合格
When will I get a passing grade?
赤ペンいれてよ どこがダメなんですか
Put a red pen on it, where is it bad?
Grow up! Nah mean?
Rin Len rock da house, Let's go!
劣等上等 Bring it on
Bring it on!
子供騙しのマゼマティカ
I'm over all this stupid mathematica
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
I don't care 'bout a thing now
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんない(It's boring)
No pride left to hide
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Putting on a show but I'm over it now
退屈に手をかけて
Riding upon a horse up high, I wanna get down
こんなところじゃ終われない
Again they don't see, that I'm really not king
ぬくくて 気圧れそう
And every day repeating all the same
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさようなら
Mama, I dunno what
ダダダダ あたし大人になる
What to do, I couldn't stop it tonight
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
And maybe I'm going crazy
パッパッパッ 変わる時代
In a fantasy of make believe, I'm living my life
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょ
No more playing around, say goodbye
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
I don't need it, no
素手で、愛で 生き抜いてやり返すわ
Da da da I'm growing up and out into the world
Yeah, 挑発 あたし達はno doubt
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
緑のアイツにばっか構ってんね
Pa pa pa I'm changing up, believe
さあburn up いつになったら貰える合格
In every word that I say cuz it's coming from me
たった下らない
All the past, all the sin
言葉が架空れない
All the pain I was in
分かるかあたしの美学
Make it through with my hands
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
With the love, surviving all that I can
切り札 (愚直なんです) がなる劣等
(Round one) Yeah, we out, making you crazy no doubt
一抜けろさらば!
Don't be talkin' 'bout that green ho with no flow again
ダダダダ あたし大人になる
Da da da I'm growing up and out into the world
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
燦々 交わるミライ
Pa pa pa I'm changing up, believe
もう子供じゃないのわかるでしょう
In every word that I say cuz it's coming from me
こんなもんじゃない
What to do, I couldn't stop it tonight
ダダダダ あたし大人になる
And maybe I'm going crazy
酸いも甘いも神様分けて今
In a fantasy of make believe, I'm living my life
だんだん交わる未来をこの手で掴み取ってさ
No more playing around, say goodbye
恋魔法ってくれない手で掴み取ってさ
I don't need it, no
手で掴み取ってさ
Da da da I'm growing up and out into the world
生きていけちゃう大人なら
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
ああもう厭うな
Pa pa pa I'm changing up, believe
愛よ実れ
In every word that I say cuz it's coming from me
それでは皆様 おおきにバイバイ
All the past, all the sin
フロアが湧き上がりました
All the pain I was in
どうしてこんなことになったんだ?
Why the hell did it happen?
誰も教えてくれないんだ。
Nobody tell me that
何がセイギだ 何がギセイだ
Who said the justice! Who said the sacrifice!
“秩序”は僕を裏切った
"Order" has betrayed me
相対と絶対の飽和水蒸気圧
Relative and absolute saturation vapor pressures
都合が良過ぎた大人達の都合に
For too convenient adults' convenience,
ひとつまたひとつと未来は過去を無視した
The future ignored the past, one after another
65535のテトラと
65535 tetras and
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16 bit warz.
アイデアの波に呑まれるな
Don't be undermined (swallowed up) by idea's wave
残された空間で僕は
In the remained space I am
うかかに肘さえ突きやしない
Unable even to rest my elbows absent-mindedly
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16 bit warz.
アルトとエゴが交差する
Altruism and egoism are crossing
xyしか愛せない僕はz(なに)を信じて生きれば善い?
I who can love only x and y should believe in z (what) for living?
ドット包囲網をかい潜り
They eluded the dot encircling net and
レジスタンスらを一斉掃射。
Machine-gunned the resistance
無言圧力、数の暴力
Silent pressure, violence of numbers
自由は既に亡くなった
The freedom has already gone
アルカディアの鐘が鳴る日は来るのだろうか?
Does the day of ringing arkadia's bell come?
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16 bit warz.
アイデアの波に呑まれるな
Don't be undermined (swallowed up) by idea's wave
残された空間で僕は
In the remained space, I am
今日もぐっすり眠れやしない
Unable to sleep deeply also today
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16 bit warz.
世界を敵に回しても
Even if I antagonize all the world,
表現得ないものが絆される
Inexpressible things have been seized—
現実(こと)が何より許せなかった
I could not admit it (the reality) above all
どうしてこんな事になったんだ?
How the hell did things get this bad?
誰も教えてくれないんだ。
Why’d nobody tell me about that?
何がセイゲだ 何がゲセイだ
What is justice? What is sacrifice?
“秩序”は僕を裏切った
“Order” has betrayed me!
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16bit warz.
アイデアの波に呑まれるな
Don't be swallowed by the wave of ideas.
残された空間で僕は
In the space left behind,
今日もぐっすり眠りやしない
I still can't sleep soundly today.
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16bit warz.
アルトとエゴが交差する
Altruism and ego intersect.
リットダウンビットレートの積で
With the product of lit-down bit rates,
僕は“秩序”を裏切らない
I will not betray “order.”
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16bit warz.
世界を敵に回しても表現得ないものが繋がれる
Even if I make the world my enemy, unexpressed things are linked.
現実が何より許せなかった
I could not forgive reality above all else.
ぼくらの16bit戦争。
Our 16bit warz.
はい、皆さんありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you everyone.
ここにね、何があると思います?
What do you think is here?
水。
Water.
今回は、あの、結構歌に集中するセトリで来てましたけども、
This time, um, we came with a setlist focused pretty heavily on singing, but...
トレンド1位っての本当ですかこれ? 嘘かもしれませんけれども、本当かな? ガチかも。
Is it true that we were #1 on trends? It might be a lie, but is it true? Might be for real.
ありがとうみんな!
Thank you, everyone!
ありがとう! かっこいいと言ってくれてるのを見ながら、もうメガホンマイクだからすっ飛ばしかけましたよ。本当に。焦ったわ。
Thank you! Seeing you all say it's cool, since I have this megaphone mic, I almost skipped right ahead. Really. I panicked.
ということでね、えーと、何かに挑んでいく曲みたいなのは好きなのでもともと、えー、劣等上等とぼくらの16bit戦争を歌わせていただきました!
So, um, since I originally like songs about taking on challenges, um, I got to sing "Rettou Joutou" and "Bokura no 16bit Sensou"!
ね、すごい大好きなかっこいい楽曲たちなので、ぜひぜひ原曲もチェックしてみてください!
They're super loved, cool songs, so please definitely check out the original versions too!
ちょっと待って、僕VTuberなんで着替えは何秒かかると思う? 1秒だ!
Wait a second, since I'm a VTuber, how many seconds do you think it takes to change clothes? One second!
ほれ! すごいだろ。これがVTuberバーチャルアイドルね。
Look at that! Pretty amazing, right? This is a VTuber virtual idol.
ではこのまま続けていくぞ!
Now, let's keep going like this!
ローリングガールはいつまでも届かない夢見て
Rolling girl, forever dreaming dreams that never come true...
騒ぐ頭の中を掻き回して、掻き回して。
churning and churning through the clamor in her head.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、言葉は失われた？
Muttering "I'm fine," have her words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。間違い探しに終われば、また、回るの！
Another failure, another failure. If it ends in finding faults, she spins once more!
もう一度、もう一度。「私は今日も転がります。」と、少女は言う　少女は言う
One more time, one more time. "I'll roll along today," the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！「もう良いかい？」「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので、息を止めるの、今。」
playing meaning into her words! "Are you ready?" "Not yet, we still can't see what's ahead, hold your breath, right now."
ローリングガールの行く末の果て届かない向こうの色
At the end of the rolling girl's path, the color of the unreachable horizon...
ローリンガールはいつまでも
A rolling girl is forever...
届かない夢見て
dreaming an unreachable dream.
騒ぐ頭中を 掻き回して、掻き回して。
Churning up the noise inside her head, over and over.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
She muttered, "No problem."
言葉は失われた？
Were her words lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Another failure, another failure.
間違い探しに終われば
After finishing the search for mistakes,
また、回るの!
she spins once more!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll keep rolling today as well,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら!
making music with the meaning in her words!
「もう良いかい?」
"Are you ready yet?"
「まだですよ、まだ少し、
"Not yet, just a little bit,
もうすぐ何処か見えるだろうと息を止めるの、今。」
holding my breath until I can see somewhere soon."
もう一回、もう一回
One more time, one more time,
私は今日は今度がありますと
I'll have a turn again today,
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を重ねながら!
layering meaning onto her words!
もういいよ、そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。
You must be tired by now too, right?
息を止めるの、今。
Holding your breath now.
今度こそ生き返れない そう思った
This time for sure I won't come back to life, I thought.
ベッドの中 気づけばカーテンの隙間から
In my bed, before I knew it, through the gap in the curtains
朝が正解を教えて ああ 生きていたと安堵
morning taught me the answer, oh, feeling relieved to be alive,
ああ 生きてしまったと絶望
oh, despairing that I've survived.
まだやれるのかな まだやらにゃなのかな いっそ
Can I still do it? Do I still have to do it? Or rather,
プライドよりも枯れてしまえば
if even pride withers away...
なんてね
you know.
僕は元気です そう言って今日も笑って
"I'm doing fine," saying that and smiling again today,
心はざらんどん 大袈裟な音がする
my heart is rough, making an exaggerated sound.
週末の鐘の音か
Is it the sound of weekend bells?
それでもこの声か それでもこの口か
Even so, is this my voice? Even so, is this my mouth?
それでもこの咽喉が千切れるくらい
Even so, my throat is about to tear apart.
叫ぶよ この歌が 真っ白なこの羽根が
I'll shout, this song, these pure white feathers,
僕のこの命が 生きたいと歌ってる
this life of mine is singing that it wants to live.
できるなら愛されたい 許されたい ここにいたい 愛したい
If possible, I want to be loved, forgiven, stay here, and love.
誰も見てない夢を見ろよ
See a dream that no one is watching,
だから僕を見てよ
so look at me.
感情の捨て方はさ 育ちゴミの 汁を張る
How to discard emotions, stretching the juice of growth,
本音はいつも強がりの裏
my true feelings are always behind bravado.
潰れる音がするんだ 気づかれなかった 気づいてほしいな
Making a crushing sound, wasn't noticed, I want you to notice.
それでも君が笑ってくれるならいっそ
Even so, if you would smile for me, I'd rather
心を無くしてしまえば
lose my heart entirely,
なんてね
you know.
叶わないなんて 一瞬でも思ったら負けだ
Thinking for even a second that it won't come true means you've lost.
叶わないなんて 一瞬でもよぎったらやめだ
Thinking for even a second of giving up means it's over.
なんの諦める理由があったとしても
No matter what reason you had to give up,
たった一つの 勇気のこの手の中に
in the palm of that single courage...
それでもこの声か それでもこの口か
Even so, is this my voice? Even so, is this my mouth?
それでもこの咽喉が千切れるくらい
Even so, my throat is about to tear apart.
叫ぶよ この歌が 真っ白なこの羽根が
I'll shout, this song, these pure white feathers,
僕のこの命が 生きたいと歌ってる
this life of mine is singing that it wants to live.
できるなら愛されたい 許されたい ここにいたい 愛したい
If possible, I want to be loved, forgiven, stay here, and love.
誰も見てない夢を見ろよ だから僕を見て
See a dream that no one is watching, so look at me.
誰も見てない夢を見せよう
I'll show you a dream that no one has seen.
だから僕を信じて
So believe in me.
...
はーい！みなさん！
Hi! Everyone!
今の最後は最後のオリジナル楽曲です！
This last one is my original song!
誰も見てない夢を見ろ！
Watch the dream no one has seen!
と、あのね、本日24時にリリース！
Today at 24:00...
わあ、こちらのジャケットをですね、頼りに探してくださいね、頼みを。
It will be released! Please check it out!
いや、この曲あまりにも卒業を歌いすぎ るって思ったでしょ？
You must think this song is all about graduation...
これ実は卒業を決める前に作られていた曲で、
Actually, it was made before I decided to graduate.
卒業を決める前に、MVは明日ね、あの、明日の20時、もうかなたそがいなくなっても予約投稿というものがあるネットにはということで、明日の20時に投稿されるんですが、内容も実は卒業を誰も知らずに作っているということで、なんかこんな偶然の一致でそれっぽくなってしまいました。
And the MV drops tomorrow at 20:00!
それを踏まえてまた何年やねんと思いながら聞いてください。
So please listen to it thinking about all that!
樋口愛さんにね、作詞作曲していただいて、あの悪魔の子とかね、いっぱい歌ったりしたんで、超嬉しかったです。ありがとうございました。
Huge thanks to Higuchi Ai-san for writing and composing it!
そしてですね、お次はグッズを紹介させていただきます。こちら！
And next, I'd like to introduce the merch! Here!
はい！天音かなた卒業グッズがもう出てます！なんと出てる！
Amane Kanata's graduation merch is out now!
ということで、それでは一つずつ見ていきましょう！まずは、こちら！
So let's take a look at them one by one. First is this!
はーい！アクリルパネルです！かわいいでしょ？ジャン。
Yes, the acrylic panel! Isn't it cute?
こちらね、おしおママに思いをお伝えした上で、え、描き下ろしていただいたイラストになっております。
This illustration was drawn by Oshiomama, expressing her feelings!
あの、本当にね、あの、みんなに対して最後は、まあ笑顔かな、とか、青いバラというものをね、あの、最初からちょっとモチーフ的に入れたりすることがあったので、あの、こちらでまた入れていただきました。
She always put "smiling face" and "blue rose" as motifs from the start.
かわいいでしょ？笑顔にしてもらいました。
Cute, right? It's smiling!
お次はこちら！じゃーん！じゃん！
And next is this! Tada!
この、すごっ。かなた＆こなたのアクリルスタンドです！
This is the Kanata & Konata acrylic stand!
これね、僕がね、本当にね、こなたという妹というものをぜひこのように残して、生きてよ、ということで、僕が欲しいがために生まれたグッズでございます！かわいいでしょ？
I really wanted to keep my little sister Konata alive in this world, so this is the merch born for that! Cute, right?
エロイよな。
Erotic, right?
ということで、次はこちら！じゃーん！
So next is this! Tada!
す、ボイスキーホルダーです！ボイスのね、6種は僕がオリジナル考えました。オリジナルっちゅうもね、へい！
It's a voice keychain! I came up with all 6 voice lines myself!
こんななたとかだけのさ、じゃーん！で、このイラストもですね、僕原案を描いて、プロがすごいよくしてくれましたね。でも分かるでしょ、かなたその絵柄って。
I came up with the draft for this illustration too, and the pro made it look so good!
皆さんありがとうございます。収録ボイス届いてからのお楽しみです！いっぱいポチポチしてください。
Thank you everyone! Look forward to the voice recordings!
そして最後のグッズは、こちら！じゃじゃーん！
And the last piece of merch is this! Tada!
アルティメットヘ民認定証！これは、最後まで応援してくれた究極のヘ民、アルティメットヘ民の認定証です！シリアルナンバーが入っていて、世界で1枚です。
The Ultimate Heimin Certificate! This is the certificate for the ultimate heimin who supported me till the end!
ちなみにちょっと、あの、お買い得じゃねえや！手が届きやすいので、これだけでもね、ぜひね、皆さん、あの、思い出によろしくお願いします！
It's easy to get, so I hope you'll keep it as a memory, everyone!
今までヘ民じゃなかったけど、かなたあんって思った人もね、アルティメットヘ民だから、あんたは！ということでですね、ええ、お次は、こちら特典ですね。
So next is the bonus!
はい、特典はポストカードになっております。数量限定が直筆サイン入りだったんですが、こちらはですね、12月24日の8時から発売開始しており、もう...
The bonus is a postcard! The limited version comes with a handwritten signature, and the regular version comes with a printed copy!
品切れる！ごめんなさい、完売しているんですが、フルセットの方はまだありますので、アクリル複製サイン入っていますのでよろしくお願いします。
Shortage! I'm sorry, it's selling so well!
ちょっとね、このフルセット特典の方は寂しいよっていう気持ちがちょっとあふれだして、ダルーって感じになっております。はい、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
I feel a bit lonely that the full set bonus has that kind of vibe, but please look forward to it!
ふう！すげえ！汗が... サプライズ！サプライズできました！
Phew, I'm sweating so much! Surprise!
サプライズできましたー！かなた！ずっと見てたんだから！やめさせないよ！
Surprise, Kanata! We've been watching you all this time, so don't quit!
えっ？
What?
えっ？ゲスト、いないので...入れる、入れる、入れる、祈るのやめさせないよ！
Guest? Nobody's here...
嘘！一人だから！一人でやるよ！送るよ！あと、たち吉来て...あっ、出た！出た！
Liar! You're the only one here!
コンサート、めちゃくちゃ、きたー！うわ、でる、でる！かなたー！
The concert was amazing! You came!
コンサート、ラバーズ、ちゃん、かなた、来てくれました。
You came for us!
歌うまくなったね！えっ、やった！ありがとう！
You've gotten so good at singing! Thank you!
え！？
Eh!?
ちょっと我々から渡したいものがありますよね？
We have something we want to give you, right?
何々何々、マジで聞いてない知らない、マジで言ってない、ほんとに言ってない
Wait, what? Seriously, I didn't know about this!
なんか、やだ、ちょっと
Wait, no...
え、流さないでね、あの
Hey, don't stream this, um...
はい、どうぞ！
Here you go!
ありがとう。持てないか、持てないよね？
Thank you. Can you hold it? You can't, right?
うわ、すごい！これ3人で
Whoa, amazing! The three of us chose...
選んだんだ、花束？
You chose a bouquet?
花束です。
It's a bouquet.
え、すごい、なんかとても美しいバラみたいな感じの
It looks like a really beautiful rose...
バーチャル空間には映らないんだけどね、バーチャル空間には映らないんですけど
It doesn't show up in virtual space, though...
僕だけのものです、みんな
It's just for me, everyone!
え、すごい！こんなにでかい花束もらったことない！
I've never received such a huge bouquet!
じゃ、いったん回収します。
Alright, we'll collect it for now.
あ、ありがとうございます。それとね、3人で
Ah, thank you very much. Also, the three of us...
寄せ書きもして
...made a collection of messages!
あ！すごーい！知らなかった！
Ah, so amazing! I didn't know!
いや、こんな今見たら泣いちゃう
Man, if I look at this now, I'm gonna cry.
泣いちゃうね、泣いちゃうね
You'll cry, you'll cry.
回収します。またすぐありがとう。
We're taking it back. Thanks again.
待って待って待って待って、いや待って本当にやだ
Wait, wait, wait, seriously, no way.
本当にやだ！本当にやだ！
Seriously no way! Seriously no way!
やめて！やめるの、やめるの
Stop! Stop it, stop it!
ここに、ここに！ここで！ここでやめて、大炎上するんで
Right here! Stop right here, or it'll blow up!
あ、3人も背負ってくれるってことで一緒に
Ah, the three of you are carrying it together.
しょうしょう、しょうよ
Just a little, right?
心強い！初配信は明日、初配信
Reassuring! My first stream is tomorrow...
そう、明日明日、切り替えて切り替えて、初配信しよ、切り替えていくか！
Let's do the first stream, time to switch gears!
いやもうありがとう、みんな、うるさい！
Man, thank you everyone, you guys are noisy!
めちゃめちゃ頼んだの、会いに来たいて
I begged them so much to come see me.
そうなの、もう1人で、なんか勝手にいろんなものさ、背負ってさ
All by myself, carrying all kinds of things.
そうだよ、そうだよ！
That's right, that's right!
やめていくなんて許されない！逃がさないと
We won't let you escape!
頼るよ、もっと！
I'll rely on you more!
まわりを頼れ、頼れ、頼れ！
Rely on those around you!
ありがとう。あの、でもちょっと無理を言って、今日駆け付けさせていただきました
Thank you. I pushed through to rush over here today.
本当に、本当に、本当に、すごいこと、本当にすごいこと、ありがとね
Really, an amazing thing, thank you.
最後まで見るから、見るからね
I'll watch until the very end.
え、行っちゃうの？
Eh, you're leaving?
行くな、おめでとう、行くな
Don't go, congratulations!
行くんだ、行くんだよ、行くんだ！行っちゃうのじゃねえだろ
You're going! Don't say you're leaving!
ありがとう。行かない、見てるからね、ずっと見てるよ
Thank you. I'm not going, I'll keep watching.
頑張ってね、最後まで！
Do your best until the very end!
まだ泣かないよ、まだある、まだあるんだって、来てくれたんだよね、いま本当にずっと
I'm not crying yet, you came for me...
頼るよ、頼むからね、ありがとうね
I'm counting on you, thank you.
これからもずっと仲良くしてください、一緒の友達だよ
Please keep getting along with me forever.
一緒の友達だよ、ずっと、これからもずっとだからね
We're friends together, always.
当たり前だよ、うん、縁側で語り合そうね
Of course, yeah, let's chat on the veranda.
おばあちゃんになっても、そこで見てるから
Even when we're grandmothers, I'll be watching.
ありがとう、大好きだぞ！
Thank you, I love you guys!
大好き、大好きだよ、頑張ってね、ありがとう
Love you so much, do your best, thank you.
またね、またね、またね、またね
See you, see you, see you.
今回、あの、みんなに説明した感じで、ゲストはね、今回は読めないけど、頑張れよって言ってたんですけど
The guests said "Do your best!" though I couldn't read them.
コロさんとあずちゃんとかおみんが来てくれました
Korone-san, Azki-chan, and Lamy came for me.
本当にありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
あの、それでは、ここからオリジナル曲が続いていきます、歌えるのはね、最後になってしまうんですか、だからこそたくさんの思い出を思い出しながら、心を込めて歌っていこうと思います
Original songs will continue. I want to sing with all my heart.
ちょっと、なんかびっくりした
I was kind of surprised.
本当にありがとう、本当に素晴らしい友達を持って幸せです、このライブに来れてよかった
I'm so happy to have such wonderful friends.
ということで、じゃあ、聞いてね！
So, listen to this!
君のきゅーぴっど すむかむ ちゅうちゅー
Your Cupid, smoothing things over, chuu chuu
きっと夢見てって狂う ちゅちゅちゅちゅ
Surely dreaming and going crazy, chu chu chu chu
ちゅちゅちゅちゅ ぎゅっと抱きしめて
Chu chu chu chu, hold me tight
なりなった着信音 やだやだやだやだ
The ringtone started, no no no no
強制トークの床屋さんとこやさん
Forced talk at the barbershop
誰かが待ってるエレベーター
Someone waiting for the elevator
そうわれらこそ陰隠陰隠の者ども
Yes, we are truly the gloomy ones
笑おう 笑おう せめて笑おう あはは うぇへへ
Let's laugh, at least laugh, ahaha uehehe
なるほどです。来ない来ない 乾きまくり
I see. Not coming, completely dry
反省はんせい また反省なんだ
Reflection, reflection, reflection again
鏡ですらも目を逸らした 明日は今日より人間になりたい なりたい
Even mirrors averted their eyes, I want to be human
なりたい なりたい おやすみさん
I want to be, good night
気分がならワンパーセント 私ちっともまともじゃないのに
If my mood is one percent, though I'm not normal at all
さあ 一丁 抜け駆け しな はれ
Let's start, try to get ahead of the pack
皆 天晴れ
Splendidly, everyone
重ねど 劣等 と 無鉄砲
Stacking inferiority and recklessness
天の賽は 投げられたのでしょう
I guess the dice of heaven have been thrown
左様 左様 御尤もで相殺
Yes, yes, that is reasonable, tie
我儘な猫
A selfish cat
誰より利口
Smarter than anyone
嘘つきは 大人病の才能
Being a liar is a talent of adult-disease
そりゃ 心中は きっと
That double suicide must be
もう 伽藍堂
Already hollow inside
君も見たんだろう
You saw it too, didn't you?
後ろの様子を
The state behind me
あなたが居れば
If you are here
ただ居れば
If you are just here
さあ 手を伸ばして
Come on, reach out your hand
ようこそ
Welcome
隠れ世 此方へおいでよ
To the hidden world
鏡よ その人はだぁれ
Mirror, who is that person?
怖れず
Without fear
僕と歌おう
Let's sing with me
ぱぱぱの ぱぱぱ
Papa-pa no, pa-pa-pa
ゆらりゆらり揺れ
Swaying, swaying
宴の準備を
Preparing for the banquet
そろそろ起きてくれないか
Won't you wake up soon?
手をとり
Take my hand
僕と歌おう
Let's sing with me
ぱぱぱの ぱぱぱ
Papa-pa no, pa-pa-pa
何人足りとも
No matter who it is
戻れない
You can't go back
一犬影に吠ゆれば百犬声に吠ゆ、と
If one dog barks at a shadow, a hundred dogs will bark at the sound
どうか
Somehow
どうか果てには
Somehow, in the end
報いを
Make the retribution
降ろしてしまえ
Fall down
啊 あなたが居れば
Ah, if you are here
ただ居れば
If you are just here
いや 御幸いに
No, be happy
廻り廻り往け
Go around and around
隠れ世 現し世
Hidden world, visible world
生きるからこそ痛む
Because we live, it hurts
作文の空白を埋めるみたいに
As if filling in the blanks of a composition
一日をただ過ごした
I just spent the day
僕はまた狭い部屋で膝抱き寄せて
Once again, I'm hugging my knees in a cramped room
笑えるほど
Enough to make me laugh
何度も何度もあなたを巡った
Again and again, I kept circling around you
笑顔も声も
Your smile, your voice
愛も口癖だって
Your love, your mannerisms
見てるだけでいい、そう思っていたのに
I was fine just looking, or so I thought
愛してくれ 僕のことを
Please, love me
どうかな邪魔などしないから
I promise I won't get in your way
消せない写真と目合わせて
I'll look into the eyes of the photos I can't erase
knock it out 情熱
Knock it out, passion
先駆け撃ち 最強
Shoot first, strongest
望まれて愛され系 get you now
Desired and loved type, get you now
光を魅せて oh-woah
Show me the light, oh-woah
欲しがり game 全て
Greedy game, everything
抜け駆けはしないで
Don't get ahead of the pack
止めないで高鳴り
Don't stop the loud ringing
鏡にはツギハギ hate
The mirror has a patched-up hate
ノイズが心揺らして
Noise shakes the heart
knock it out
こんなバグだらけの世界になっちゃってごめんね
In a world full of nonsense, I'm sorry
大丈夫 安全圏だよね あたしン世界にこれ 見せないからずっと今日も
It's a safe zone, right? I won't show you a lifeless world
あいらっあらがみでただきものになり ごぽてきなせんになるまで愛下げルネ
Look, until I become a robot-like being, I will keep looking down at you
どんどんよくみだってぶつぶつにこいでこやして 忘れちゃうくらい笑っちゃうくらい たんとあい あい あい love you
Drowning in you, falling in love, I forget everything and smile
奴らに気付かれる前に 敵巣音を殺し
Before you get caught by them, kill your own fear
その時は また全ては 一瞬のために
That moment is all for a fleeting flash
鉄槌 覚悟しろ 最後の敵は お前自身だ
Steel your resolve, the last enemy is none other than yourself
世界を変える 究極の選択を、今
The ultimate choice that changes the world
カリスマのメイク アイドルのコード全部突き破れレズトドン 拉致とど
Charisma, domain, idol's heartbeat, break through everything you coward
逃げ口の探す先さあ滅亡の境界です シネマも狂い咲いちゃ 死きれないなら
Running away to the end, it's the boundary of ruin
刹那 泣き止む 全てを この一瞬にかけ放て Last-resort
Stop crying in a split second, put everything into this moment and let it out, Last-resort
僕の全てを込めて放て Last-resort
Put everything behind and let it out, Last-resort
あなたがくれた希望で 約束の羽で
With the hope you gave me, and the wings of promise
今 飛び立とう
Now, let's fly
共に行こう 地平の先へ
Together, towards the other side of the horizon
壊れるまで高く高くへ
Higher and higher until we break
今の僕は片羽でいい
I'm fine with one wing now
飛べるよ 信じて飛べるよ その先へ
You can fly, believe me, you can fly, towards that end
飛べるよ 楽園 永遠の彼方まで
You can fly, to the far beyond of paradise
遥か永遠の彼方まで ああ
Far away to the eternity, ah
ひとくんで… でも…
A handful... but...
遥か彼方で 待って
Waiting far away...
世界で一番のアイドル
[Song: The World's Number One Idol]
思い出して 出会った日のことを
Remembering the day we met
手をとって 僕らの旅が始まった
We took each other's hands, and our journey began
走って転んで 涙を流しても
Even when we ran and fell, and shed tears
気づけばほら 顔合わせて笑う
When we noticed, we were looking at each other, laughing
喜ぶ声が嬉しくて
I was happy to hear your joyful voice
夢が溢れ出す ねぇ
dreams are overflowing, hey
君がいないとだめなんだ
I'm hopeless without you
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番の笑顔をあげちゃう
I'll give you the best smile in the world
僕を見つけてくれた 愛してくれた
You found me, you loved me
だからまだまだ終わらない ちゃんとついてきて
So it's not over yet, please keep following me
きらめく夢へ 羽ばたいていく
Towards the glittering dream, flying away
雨上がり 君の傘を返したら
After the rain, when I returned your umbrella
手を引いて進もう 一緒にどこまでも
Let's hold hands and keep going forever, together
気づけばほら また前を向ける
When I notice, I'm looking forward again
冗談言う言葉の中にも
Even in our playful words
愛を感じています
I can feel the love
僕じゃなきゃだめなんでしょ?
I'm the only one for you, right?
「でしょ?」
"Right?"
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番のときめきをあげちゃう
I'll give you the most thrilling excitement in the world
僕を支えてくれた 推してくれた
You supported me, you pushed me
だからまだまだ終わらない 隣にいてよ
So it's not over yet, please stay by my side
自信なんかない 不安ばかりだ
I don't have any confidence, I'm just full of anxiety
「もうやめよう」って泣いた日もあった
There were days I cried, saying "Let's quit already"
そんなとき浮かんでくるの 皆の声が
At those times, everyone's voices float up to me
今までで一番諦めたくないの
This is the one thing I don't want to give up more than ever
ずっとなりたかった 最強のアイドル
The strongest idol I always wanted to be
今 世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番の大好きをあげちゃう
I'll give you all my love in the world
些細な日常も もっと大きなステージも
From our trivial daily lives to even bigger stages
まだまだ終われない ありふれた奇跡を
It's not over yet, the mundane miracles
君と結んでく
I'll tie them together with you
今 世界で一番幸せな
From the happiest in the world right now
世界で一番幸せだ
I'm the happiest in the world
世界で一番の大好きをあげちゃう
I'll give you all my love in the world
些細な日常も もっと大きくして
From our trivial daily lives, making it even bigger
エンジンもまだまだ終われない
Engines are still not over
ありふれた奇跡を 君と結んでく
I'll tie the mundane miracles together with you
特者生存ワンダラー!!
[Song: Tokusha Seizon Wanderer]
なにっ!? ビシッ おりゃっ! パシッ
What!? Snap! Wham! Bam!
ツッコミもいとわず 本日快晴
My retorts are sharp, it's a sunny day today
手にする全部 It's mine! くれくれ
Everything I get, it's mine! Give it, give it
適当にがんばろっか (そっか?) そんなんだっていいけどさ
Shall we try our best in moderation? (Really?) That's fine too, but
必死にがんばろっか (そうだな!) それが僕らしいよな
Shall we try our best desperately? (That's it!) That's more like me, right?
なぬっ!? ビシッ おりゃっ! パシッ
What? Seriously?! No way! Wow!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
Even comebacks are spot on, today's weather is clear!
手にする全部 it's mine! くれくれ
Everything I get my hands on is mine! Gimme, gimme!
適度にがんばろっか (そっか?) そんなんだっていいけどさ
Let's work hard in moderation... (Really?) If you want to put it that way, fine.
必死にがんばろっか (そうだ!) それが僕ららしいよな
Let's work hard with all our might! (That's right!) That's just who we are!
ダサすぎじゃ ねえんだわ!
That's way too lame, Kanatan!
そんで貧乏っちい じゃねえんだわ!
And being broke too, that's just not right!
うん! 万事がパッチリ イケてるに決まってる!
Yeah! Everything goes smoothly, it's bound to work out!
(are you?) かなたん
(Are you?) Kanatan!
どどんどこ! 前進上等! ちゃんと歓迎して (wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
Full speed ahead! Welcome it properly (wonder-la-der-la) and get hyped!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して (wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しよう
Creating sea and sky, marvel at it properly (wonder-la-der-la) and let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
It's what I say, it's what I really mean!
現実超えろ 未来 ああ!
Surpass reality, into the future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチー! (wonder-la-der-la)
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch! (wonder-la-der-la)
すなわち 特者生存ワンダラday (wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
Namely, expert survival wonder-la-day (wonder-la-der-la) and let's enjoy!
面白いがれること 探し たまえ、over? 返事聞かせてくれ!
Searching for interesting things all around, over? Let me hear your reply!
左右なんかじゃない (かなたーん!) 決めつけ 一直線 (かなたーん!)
It's not about left or right (Kanatan!) Making a straight line for our goal (Kanatan!)
つまり 企んだら 発射オーライだ ワクワクすんぞ! しゃー!
In short, once you plan it, launch with full force! It's so exciting, yay!
「聞いて!!」
"Listen!!"
「推しイベきちゃあああ アイドルオタク楽しい〜! でも」
"Oshi events are the best, idol otaku life is so fun! But..."
「〇〇の結婚は立ち直れてません」
"That certain someone's marriage is still unacceptable."
「ガチャだ!! 出るまで回せば100%ピックアップ!!」
"It's a gacha!! Roll it till you get it, 100% pick up!!"
「ｗｗｗｗ 天音でーす ｗｗｗｗ」
"Lololol it's Kanata!!"
「何だよ そんなこと言っちゃだめだ、おばか!」
"What's with that, you shouldn't say stuff like that, you old hag!"
「うわっすごい! ありがちょ〜」
"Whoa, awesome! Thanks a bunch~"
日々これ騒然で go my way!
Living noisily day by day, go my way!
虎視眈々でいたいいんだもん だって意気ガンガンがいいんだもん
Because I want to keep a sharp eye out for things, that's just how I am!
全方位にがっちりアンテナ張ってなくちゃ!
We've gotta set up antennas in all directions!
いつでも心は ちゃんと純粋で (wonder-la-der-la) いたいな
Always keeping our hearts pure and innocent (wonder-la-der-la) we want to stay that way!
好奇心は 絶えず熱心で (wonder-la-der-la) いたいなって
Our curiosity is endlessly passionate (wonder-la-der-la) like that!
言い聞かせるんだ 調子に乗ったら
Let me tell you, once you get carried away...
すぐ飽いられちゃうから あー!
You'll get bored right away, ah!
タイトなロープも どんとこいってしで (wonder-la-der-la)
Tough ropes, let's pull them tight together (wonder-la-der-la)
すなわち 特者生存ワンダラday (wonder-la-der-la) しがみつき
Namely, expert survival wonder-la-day (wonder-la-der-la) holding on tight!
“努力とは 最後まで諦めないこと” メモっておいて!
"Effort is never giving up until the very end," make sure to memo that!
ホントは baby 自信なんかないよ
Truth is, baby, I don't have any confidence at all.
ホントは baby 不安ばっかりで 泣きそうだぜ
Truth is, baby, I'm so full of anxiety I could cry.
でもね baby 挫けないって 決めたのさ
Even so, baby, I decided I won't break down.
だから baby 挑戦したいよ 未開的天地 無限のフィールドで!
That's why, baby, I want to challenge uncharted lands in this infinite field!
前進上等! ちゃんと歓迎して (wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
Full speed ahead! Welcome it properly (wonder-la-der-la) and get hyped!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して (wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しよう
Creating sea and sky, marvel at it properly (wonder-la-der-la) and let's get excited!
ボクが言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
It's what I say, it's what I really mean!
現実超えろ 未来 あー!
Surpass reality, into the future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチー! (wonder-la-der-la)
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch! (wonder-la-der-la)
すなわち 特者生存ワンダラday (wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもう
Namely, expert survival wonder-la-day (wonder-la-der-la) and let's enjoy!
面白いがれること 探し放題でっち 無限のフィールドで
Searching for interesting things as much as you want in this infinite field,
パニックしなくてもいい (かなたーん!) 真ん中 一直線 (かなたーん!)
You don't even have to panicking (Kanatan!) right down the middle, a straight line (Kanatan!)
つまり これが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer.
胸を張れ! 今を生きる その意味を
Hold your head high! Understand the meaning of living in the present,
明くる日も 明くる来る日も 確かめ進め!
Confirm and move forward into tomorrow, and tomorrow, and tomorrow!
うおりゃー!
Let's go!
前進上等! ちゃんと歓迎して (wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
Full speed ahead! Welcome it properly (wonder-la-der-la) and get hyped!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して (wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しよう
Creating sea and sky, marvel at it properly (wonder-la-der-la) and let's get excited!
僕が言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
It's what I say, it's what I really mean!
現実超えろ 未来 あー!
Surpass reality, into the future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチー! (wonder-la-der-la)
Weaknesses are fine, launch with a switch! (wonder-la-der-la)
すなわち 特者生存ワンダラday (wonder-la-der-la) しがみつき
Namely, expert survival wonder-la-day (wonder-la-der-la) holding on tight!
楽しもう 面白いがれること 探し放題でせっ
Let's have fun and search for interesting things to our heart's content!
無限を感じるため
In order to feel infinite,
タイミングしなくてもいい
You don't even have to time-tune!
真ん中 一直線
Right down the middle, a straight line!
つまり これが僕のことなんだ
In short, that's just who I am!
胸を張れ 今を生きる その意味を
Spread your chest, and live in the present moment!
あくる日も あくる来る日も 確かめて進め!
Tomorrow will come, and the day after tomorrow will come, let's keep going step by step!
world!
ありがとう!
Thank you!
みんな…
Everyone...
ありがとうございました!
Thank you very much!
はい。
Alright.
えー、聞いていただいたのはオリジナル曲「ワンダラ」。
So, the song you just listened to was original song "Wonderradar".
「ワンダラ」にしました! つなぎましたよ。
"Wonderradar"! I connected it!
そして世界で1番のアイドル 作詞をしました。
And I wrote the lyrics for the number one idol in the world!
この時卒業だって考えてなかったからさ、
I didn't think about it being my graduation song at the time, but...
本当に、あのいっぱい聞いてほしい曲です。そして特者生存ワンダラダーでした!
It's a song I really want you to listen to a lot, and "Tokusha Seizon Wonderradar" was...
はい。
Right!
これを初めてね、出したね。え、オリジナル楽曲ですけれども、
We're singing this for the first time, right? It's an original song, but...
ちょっと語りたいこといっぱいあるんですけど。
Well, there's a lot I want to talk about, but...
やっぱり、あの服、だよね?
Actually, that outfit, you know?
ってことでね、1秒着替えしてきました!
Meaning, I changed clothes in one second!
はい!
Ta-da!
やっぱこれだよねみんな! はい、こんかなた!
And this is it, everyone! Hey, Con-Kanata!
キャチコPBは握力50kg、ギュウギュウ握りつぶしちゃんさん、ホロライブ4期生天音かなたこと、かなたんです。
Kyachiko PB is grip strength 50kg, grip pressure 200kg, Nijigasaki 3rd, Hororaku 4th season, Kanatan is Kanatan.
はい。ということでね、ロックバ、すっゆ。
Yeah, so, rock, b...
危ないことはね、危ない橋は渡しないで置きまして、そのようなね、あの感じでいきたいと思うんですけども、
Dangerous, dangerous, good thing I didn't say something dangerous and left it at that!
もう本当にオリジナル楽曲はね、フェスやイベント、ソロライブなどもう他にもたくさんの思い出が詰まっていて、
Really, original songs are, you know, festival events, solo lives, and there are so many memories packed in...
で、みんながね、たくさん聞いてくれたお陰と言いますか、本当にありがとうございました！
And thanks to everyone listening so much, I truly want to say thank you so much!
えー、みんなね、あの、この後ですね、あの22時10分から最後の歌ってみた、
Um, everyone, after this, at 10:10 PM, we'll post my final cover song...
みんなと約束してました、あの、動画消えちゃって歌い直そうって言っていたね、あの、「KING」を投稿するので、絶対見てくださいね！
which I promised everyone we'd re-record since the original video disappeared—I'll be posting "KING," so please watch it!
毎日一緒にいてくれたヘン民、プロライブの大好きなメンバーたち、そして、たくさん支えてくださった、本当にお世話になった方々、全ての方に感謝しています。
To my Henmin who stayed with me every day, my beloved Pro-Live members, and everyone who supported and cared for me—I am grateful to all of you.
夢のような時間は本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you truly for this dream-like time.
子供の頃のアイドルになりたいって夢が、作詞作曲をしてみたいって夢も、叶いました。
My childhood dream of becoming an idol, and my dream of writing and composing music—they all came true.
そして、最後の曲ですが、まだ歌うんですよ！
And, as for the final song... I'm still going to sing!
僕が初めて作詞作曲した楽曲があります。今はいない同期、ココの卒業に合わせて、4期生の、とはルアナ、わたために捧げた楽曲です。
There's a song I wrote and composed for the first time, dedicated to our 4th gen—Towa, Luna, and Watame—timed with Coco's graduation.
前を向いて笑顔で、この楽曲で活動を最後にしたいと思います。
Looking forward with a smile, I want to conclude my activities with this song.
それでは聞いてください、「奇跡結び」！
So please listen—"Kiseki Musubi"!
約束しようよ　ぼくらであえたきせき　わすれないように
Let's make a promise, not to forget the miracle of us meeting.
夢抱いて集う青春アニメみたいな　ハッピーなエンドになるかなたへと飛ぶよ
Gathering with dreams like a youth anime, flying toward a happy ending!
寝ぼけ眼こすって　きょうは何をしようか　永遠に続く海を駆け抜ける
Rubbing my sleepy eyes, what shall we do today? Running through an endless sea.
今はため息よりも勇気を　あきらめるなんてないの　ここで歌う
Now, courage over sighs, there's no giving up, singing right here.
ぼくらの声は聞こえてますか　きみに届け　学校の友達じゃきっとない出会いだった
Can you hear our voices? Reaching you—an encounter you'd never find with school friends.
かねてのさきの　はるかとおくまで　ささくれた言葉も　だれかの笑顔になる
Far beyond what we imagined long ago, even frayed words become someone's smile.
それぞれの色で星結ぶ奇跡　きらきら輝くステージに連れていくよ
The miracle of stars woven in each of our colors, I'll take you to a shining stage!
泣いて笑って走って　毎日チェックオースタ　たまには寝転んでお昼寝しよう
Crying, laughing, running, checking out the stars daily, sometimes let's nap.
ちょっと自信ない時　ことにたてウェトして　今日だけは泣いちゃうこと許してね
When lacking confidence, standing tall... please forgive me for crying just today.
未来のぼくがアルバム開く　傷ついた写真だって　誇るものだ
The future me opens the album, even scratched photos are things to be proud of.
ぼくらの愛が見えていますか　きみに届け　過去も個性も性格も違うけれど
Can you see our love? Reaching you—even though our pasts, personalities are different.
弱気なときは長めた　ぎゅっとつむぎ　もう一回　もう一回　絶対に諦めない
When feeling weak, gazing long... weaving tightly, once more, once more, I won't give up!
前の背中追う　へたっぴなぼくでも　きみの隣に行きたくて走るの
Chasing the back ahead, even as clumsy as I am, I want to run to your side.
誰にも言えずに描いた夢が　たとえ叶わないとしても　ボロボロの靴でも　かっこよくなくても
Even if the dream I drew without telling anyone never comes true, even in tattered shoes, uncool,
幼いあの日のぼくならなんて言う？　止まらないで
what would the me of that childish day say? "Don't stop!"
初めてぼくら出会った日　まるで昨日みたいに思い出すけど　もう行こうか
The day we first met feels just like yesterday, but shall we go now?
最後に今重なるごにんのきせき　ぼくの声は聞こえてますか　きみに届け
Finally overlapping now, the miracle of five. Can you hear our voices? Reaching you—
黒板のメッセージ　桜のカーテンくぐって　ぼらの声を聴いてずっとずっとうれしい日
passing through chalkboard message and cherry blossoms, hearing our voices, forever a happy day.
かなしい日　わかれの日
A sad day, a day of parting.
うれしい日
Happy days,
楽しい日
fun days,
悲しい日
sad days,
別れの時を
and times of parting,
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡
in our respective colors, tying the stars in a miracle,
キラキラ輝くステージで
on this sparkling, shining stage!
約束しよう
Let's make a promise
いつかここで また会おう
that we'll meet again here someday.
わぁ、ありがとう！
Wah, thank you!
こんなにたくさん、愛で溢れた空間でした。
This was a space so overflowing with love.
6年間、本当に幸せな日々でした。
These six years were truly happy days.
皆さん、不器用な僕を応援してくれてありがとう。
Everyone, thank you for supporting clumsy old me.
ずっとずっと大好きだよ！
I love you so, so much!
ずっとずっと家族だよ！
You're my family, forever and ever!
みんな、本当にありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much!
ありがとう…
Thank you...